Venezuelan - Bachelor Degree in Computing Science

(+1) 407-601.9438 victorteppa@gmail.com Kissimmee, FL. 34744

https://vteppaweb.github.io/resume/index.html

**About Me** 

Hi, my name is Victor Teppa and welcome to my digital portfolio. With a Bachelor's degree

in Computer Science, great creativity and knowledge in the design and development of

software applications.

Determination to learn new technologies, proactive attitude, written and verbal

communication skills are just some of my key strengths, which will make me an asset to

your organization.

Others key strengths that I possess include, but are not limited to, the following:

• My knowledge on life cycle development software.

• Strong desire to learn.

• Solid understanding of responsive web design mobile first.

My knowledge on front end web UI / UX frameworks and libraries.

• Object-Oriented Programming Principles.

I enjoy being challenged and engaging with projects that require me to work outside my

comfort zone.

For the last 12 months, I have been learning new technologies on my own and updating my

knowledge from home, it has been a lonely, difficult and challenging process. However, my

passion for web development has increased as well as my self-confidence.

My favorite quote:

"Everybody wants to go to heaven, but nobody wants to die"

- Unknown

Venezuelan - Bachelor Degree in Computing Science

### **Experience**

#### **Website Front End Design & Development**

Victor Teppa Digital Portfolio Orlando, United States. 2020 - 2021.

- Design website look & feel.
- Create responsive and mobile first web design using Bootstrap4 framework.
- Analysis, Design and Implementation of SEO best practices, Google Search Visibility,
  On-Page Ranking Optimization Factors.
- GIT-HUB, BOOTSTRAP4, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript DOM/ES6, Google Chrome Developer Tool, Sublime Text Editor, VS Code.
- Creation of JavaScript and React.js mini projects.

#### **Front End Web Developer**

GeoSnapShot Sydney, Australia. 2015 – 2017.

- Maintenance of the web pages look & feel.
- Evaluation of new changes under new web templates.
- Create responsive HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript web templates.
- Work on changes using (GIT-HUB, BOOTSTRAP, HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript, Sublime Text Editor).

#### **Web Application Developer**

MS21Consulting. Venezuela. 2012 - 2013.

- Analyse, design, development and maintenance of the desktop, web applications, web services and windows services implemented.
- Responsible for the development of Front End and Back End of the projects.
- Languages: HTML, CSS, C#. NET, JavaScript, ASP.NET, ADO.NET, SQL Server.
- Architectures: SOA, MVC and 3-Tier.

Venezuelan - Bachelor Degree in Computing Science

#### **Analysts & Web Developer App**

NewTech Sistemas, C.A. Venezuela. 2009 – 2012.

Design and development of web applications to supervise and monitoring the products samples of the sales department of multinational 3M Manufacture Company.
 Software Used: IBM I-Series AS/400, MS-IE 7-8, Firefox 4.0, MS-Office, IBM Lotus Notes 8.5, Dreamweaver, Photoshop, VS.Net 2003/2010, MS-Project, Reporting Services 2007, QlinkView 9.0, Cisco IP Communicator.

### **Front End Web Application Developer**

Grupo SMS, C.A. Venezuela. 2007 – 2009.

- Design and Development of new web applications. The most important projects developed using this programs were:
  - 1. Creation of a Microsoft SharePoint web application to supervise and monitoring the workflow of the process of all departments of the multinational company: Movistar Telefonica Venezuela. Project duration: 10 months.
  - 2. Collaboration in the design and development of the Look & Feel of web applications.
- **Software Used:** IE 6-7, Firefox, MS-Office, Dreamweaver, Photoshop, VS.Net 2005, MS-Project, MS-Reporting Services 2005, MS-SQL Server 2005, MS-SharePoint Server and SharePoint Designer 2007.
- Architectures: 3-Tier, MVC and SOA.

**Venezuelan – Bachelor Degree in Computing Science** 

#### **Education:**

Nueva Esparta University.

Bachelor Degree in Computer Science. Caracas – Venezuela.

#### **Courses & Seminaries:**

- CodeWithMosh.com
  - The Ultimate Git Mastery Course.

Understand Git – version control system. 2021.

- Mastering React.

Understand React inside out and boost your career prospects. 2021.

- The Ultimate JavaScript Mastery Series - Part 2.

Object-oriented Programming principles in JavaScript. 2021.

- The Ultimate JavaScript Mastery Series - Part 1

Essential ECMAScript 6 JavaScript features for web developers. 2021.

Coursera.org by UCDAVIS University of California.

SEO - Search Engine Optimization.

Optimization / Fundamentals / Best Practices to Optimize a Website for Search. 2020.

Coursera.org by the Hong Kong University of Science and Technology.

Front End Web UI Frameworks and Tools.

Bootstrap, Angular, Node.js, NPM, LiteServer, JSON, Git, CSS Pre-processors Less and Sass. 2020.

Coursera Project Network.

Position Elements on a Page with CSS. HTML5, CSS3. 2020.

Coursera.org by University of Michigan.

Front End Web Design, Development and Coding. HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap4 and Advanced Responsive Design. 2020.

**Venezuelan - Bachelor Degree in Computing Science** 

## TAFE Ultimo, New South Wales.

Web Design & Development (Certificate III and IV). Sydney, Australia. 2014 – 2015.

#### Navitas English Institute.

- Academic English level 2 and 3.
- IELTS Preparation Course.
- General English Course.
- FCE Cambridge First Certificate English.

Sydney - Brisbane, Australia.

2013 - 2014

## Centro Integral de Comunicación Visual.

- Adobe After Effects 7.0 Pro
- Macromedia Fireworks MX 2004
- Adobe Flash MX 2004 Advanced Development (Action Script). Caracas, Venezuela. 2003 2006.

#### CASE Institute.

Web Design. Caracas – Venezuela. 2001

#### Instituto de Capacitación Técnica KEYS.

Networks Seminary. Caracas – Venezuela. 2000

### Luisa Cáceres de Arismendi Institute.

Technical repair and maintenance of personal computers. Caracas – Venezuela. 1997 Venezuelan - Bachelor Degree in Computing Science

### Hard Skills (Computer):

- Life Cycle of Web Applications.
- Object-Oriented Programming Principles.
- SEO.
- Mobile First Responsive Web Design.
- REST-API: React Axios package for XMLHttpRequest / JSON Placeholder.
- Basic Knowledge of ASP.NET, MVC, Razor, C#, LINQ, Entity Framework, SQLServer.
- CMS: DNN / Site core / Microsoft SharePoint Designer
- Learning Management Systems (eLearning).
- Adobe & Macromedia: Fireworks / Photoshop / After Effects.
- Video, Audio and Image Edition.
- Front End Web UI / UX Frameworks and Libraries.



### **Soft Skills:**

- Bilingual: English / Spanish.
- Multicultural Mindset, Self-Learner, Proactive, Disciplined and Communicative.
- Detail Oriented and Organized.
- CPR and First Aid Certification.
- Fitness and Personal Trainer Certifications.
- Culinary Skills.